A Finding Aid to the Maryette Charlton papers, circa 1890-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Major Film Projects, 1904-2007; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 18.8 Linear feet Boxes 43-61, 81-82, FC 90-91, OV 87; 0.34 Gigabytes ER01
  - Frederick and Lillian Kiesler, 1938-2004; 8.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 45)
      - Photographs of Frederick Kiesler, 1963-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 16-17)
        Oversized photograph housed in Box 81
      - Photographs of Frederick Kiesler with Artwork, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Slides of Frederick Kiesler, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Photographs of Exhibition Installations, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Photograph of "Kiesler's Last Request" by Will Barnet, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - Photographs and Negatives of Kiesler Exhibition, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - Slides of Kiesler Exhibition Reception, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - Yale School of Architecture Lecture, 1947; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel Includes transcript. (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - "Architecture - Civilization" Lecture, 1958 September 20; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel Includes transcript. (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Artists Club - "Environmental Sculpture" Lecture, 1961 January 20; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - Lecture at Eugene, Oregon, 1962 March 6; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel Includes transcript. (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 46)
      - "Lecture on Space" and "Acoustic in Architecture" Lecture (1965), Digitized Audio, 2014; Archival Resource Key; 0.34 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER01)
      - New York University Seminar, 1965 February 3; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
      - New York University Seminar Transcript, 1965 February 10; Archival Resource Key (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - New York University Seminar, 1965 February 17; Archival Resource Key; 4 Sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
      - New York University Seminar, 1965 February 24; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
      - New York University Seminar, 1965 March 10; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - New York University Seminar, 1965 March 17; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Interview Transcript at New Harmony, IN, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Interview Transcript for WBAI, 1965 September 23; Archival Resource Key (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Symposium Panel Discussion on Film Transcript, circa 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - "Diary - Nivolo, Penthouse A", 1961 January 26; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - "Diary, August 18", circa 1961; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Piero Dorazio Discusses Frederick Kiesler's Writing, 1961 May 5; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 47)
      - "Kiesler - Dorazio", circa 1961; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - "Robert Whitehead", 1962; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - "Erick Hawkins", 1962 August 19; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - "(Burgess) Meredith - (Edgard) Varese", circa 1962; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - "Space and Dance - Shirley Broughton", circa 1965; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - WBAI Radio Discussion with Eric Hawkins, Lucia Dlugoszewski, and Frederick Kiesler, 1965 June 17; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Film Footage of Contemporary Artwork, 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel Notes on film can read "F. Kiesler 1970." and "Contemp artwork including Warhol, Baldessari, Richard Hamilton" Regular 8 mm (Box 47, Folder 7)
        Motion picture film stored separately in film can numbered FC 90
      - "Maryette Charlton about Frederick Kiesler" Interview with Gunda Luyken, 1995 April 28; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette Includes transcript. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Lillian Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 47)
      - Biographical Material, 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Legal Documents, 1938-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Woodward School, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Address Book, circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Small Sketch of Birds, circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Readings and Lecture Engagements, 1985-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Mailing Lists for Exhibitions, 1986-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Vienna Trip, 1988-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - Performance Information, 1996-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - Resumes, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 18)
      - Estate Paper, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - Birthday Party Guest List, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Penthouse A, 56th Avenue, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 21)
      - Book Appraisal, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - Burial, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Lillian Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 48)
      - Burial, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Memorial Service, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Obituary, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - General Correspondence, 1970-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Frances Baumgartner Correspondence, 1978-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - "Kiesler Archives" Interview Transcripts, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 6)
        Transcripts of Lillian Kiesler interviewing several people about their recollections of Frederick Kiesler including Maryette Charlton, Inez Garson, Frederick and Reinhold Heller, Lucia Dlugoszewski, Jack Lenore Larson, and others.
      - WNYC Interview of Lillian Kiesler and Maryette Charlton, 1978; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel Includes transcript. (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - "About Hans Hofmann" Interview with Lillian Kiesler, 1979 July 22; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - "Louise Varese" Interview, 1980 October 11-12; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Lillian Kiesler Interviewed by Maryette Charlton, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - "Kiesler Archives" Interview with Lillian Kiesler, 1994 April 8; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
      - "Kiesler Archives" Interview with Lillian Kiesler Duplicates, 1994 April 8; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Hi8) Duplicate; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) Duplicates (Box 48, Folder 13-14)
      - Typescript Draft of Endless Innovations Foreword, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Annotated Typescript Draft of Endless Innovations, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Lillian Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 49)
      - Annotated Typescript Draft of Endless Innovations, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
      - Endless Innovations: Frederick Kiesler's Theory and Scenic Design, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Melody Playscript, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous Writings, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Printed Material, 1950-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Christmas Cards Designed by Lillian Kiesler, circa 1990-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Lillian Kiesler Retrospective Guestbook, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Lillian Kiesler Photographs with Friends, 1967-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - "Cafe Wall" Photograph, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Memorial Service Photographs, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Memorial Album, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Performances by Lillian Kiesler and Maryette Charlton, circa 1970-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 49, Folder 13)
        "Red Slide," "Bosho 5x2 Rehearsal," and "Dreaming Out Loud Dance"
      - Alfred Barr Reading "Kiesler's Galaxy" and Lillian Kiesler Reading Letters, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels Duplicates; 1 Sound tape reel Original (Box 49, Folder 14-15)
      - Maryette Charlton Introduction and Alfred Barr Reading "Kiesler's Galaxy", 1972; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound tape reels Duplicates; 1 Sound tape reel Original (Box 49, Folder 16-17)
      - Printed Material on "Kiesler's Galaxy", 1972-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - Lillian Kiesler Reading Lectures by Other Artists, 1985 December 17; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Lillian Kiesler at Whitney Museum "Frederick Kiesler" Exhibition, 1989 February 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - Lillian Kiesler Reading Hans Hofmann Letters, 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Lillian Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 50)
      - "Existentialism Rough Footage", 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) Duplicate; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) Original (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - "Lillian Kiesler", 1992 December 18; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - "On Theater" Lecture at Columbia University School of Architecture, 1994 January 24; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Lillian Kiesler: On The Head of a Pin by Jo Andres, circa 2001; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Show Magazine from Box 44, Folder 24, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Frederick Kiesler 1890-1965 from Box 45, Folder 6, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Friedrich Kiesler: Inside the Endless House from Box 45, Folder 7, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Photograph of Frederick Kiesler From Box 45, Folder 17, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Photostatic Copies of "Kiesler's Galaxy" from Box 49, Folder 18, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Das Archiv Des Visionars Poster from Box 45, Folder 11, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 87)
    - Footage of Contemporary Artwork, 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 8mm (Item FC 90)
  - Lenore Tawney, 1943-2007; 8.2; Archival Resource Key
    This series includes research material for Charlton's film about Lenore Tawney, a pioneer in the fiber arts. Among the files are correspondence, exhibition catalogs, printed material, artifacts, and mail art exchanged between Charlton and Tawney. There are 2 sound tape reels and 1 film reel.
    - Letters to Maryette Charlton, 1965-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 5-7)
    - Memorial, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Guggenheim Application for Film Grant, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Lenore Tawney Interview, 1967 November 19; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Lenore Tawney Film, Archival Resource Key (Box 50)
      - Film Budget and Expenses, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Screening Notes, 1961-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Film Distribution Conference, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - "Film Information" Scrapbook, 1962-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Film Soundtrack Notes, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 15-16)
      - Film Editing Logbook, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - "Pierre Boulez's Eclat" for Soundtrack, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Research and Notes on "Crafts", 1963-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Exhibition Files Disbound Scrapbook, 1960-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 1-4)
    - Art in America, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Lenore Tawney: A Retrospective, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Lenore Tawney: Signs on the Wind, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "Weavings" Printed Material, 1983-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Muktananda" Printed Material, 1976-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Lenore Tawney Exhibition Catalogs, 1961-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 10-11)
    - Group Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1963-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 12-13)
    - Craft Horizons Magazines, 1964-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Assorted Magazines, 1966-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - News Clippings, 1967-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1943-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Disbound Mail Art Scrapbook, circa 1960-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Disbound Mail Art Scrapbook, circa 1960-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - Framed Tapestry Photograph, circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Tapestry, circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Oversized tapestry housed in Box 81.
    - Artifact, circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 52, Folder 6)
      Cardboard box decorated with paper and twine.
    - Miscellaneous Artifacts, circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 52, Folder 7)
      Includes a dreamcatcher, empty tin box, cardboard box with rocks glued inside, and other objects.
    - "Blue Cloud on Green Grass and Wind", circa 1960; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 91)
    - Oversized Life Magazine from Box 51, Folder 15, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Tapestry from Box 52, Folder 5, circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
  - Dorothy Miller, 1904-1994; 8.3; Archival Resource Key
    The subseries consists of material on Charlton's films about Dorothy Miller, the influential first curator of the Museum of Modern Art, and contains important research material on Miller's curatorial work. Included is correspondence, exhibition catalogs, annual reports, printed material, a scrapbook about the film, and photographic material, including images of Miller.
    There are also 6 sound tape reels and 1 sound cassette. Several reels are edited versions of the Alfred Barr recording of "Kiesler's Galaxy" that are also found in the Kiesler subseries. However, these particular recordings were used in the Dorothy Miller film.
    - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 53)
      - Jeffers, Wendy, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
      - Miller, Dorothy, 1963-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
      - Russell, John, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence about Dorothy Miller Film, 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Annotated Appointment Calendar for Venice Trip, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "Conversations in Venice" Notebook, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - American Film Institute Application and Drafts, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
    - Film Bills and Receipts, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Film Notes, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Film Disbound Scrapbook, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 13-15)
      Includes correspondence, screening notes, publicity, and other material.
    - Museum of Modern Art - New Horizons in American Art (1936), Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Museum of Modern Art Exhibition Catalogs, 1942-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 53, Folder 17-20)
    - Museum of Modern Art Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
    - Museum of Modern Art Annual Reports, 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 3-4)
    - Venice 31 Beinnale Exhibition Catalog, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Art News, 1963-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 6-7)
    - The New Yorker, 1963-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 8-9)
    - Art in America, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Tracking the Marvelous, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - News Clippings, 1963-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 12)
      Oversized clippings housed in Box 81.
    - Printed Material, 1962-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 13-14)
    - Alfred and Victoria Barr Printed Material, 1952-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of Dorothy Miller and Family, 1904-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Photographs of Venice Biennale, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Transparencies of Louise Nevelson Sculpture Installation, Venice Biennale, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
    - Slides of Art and Events, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 55, Folder 3-6)
      Consists of 4 boxes of slides showing artwork, exhibitions, installations, and openings. The bulk of the images are of the Venice Biennale and Louise Nevelson.
    - Dorothy Milller Recording, 1990 February 13; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - "Maryette Charlton's Copy" of Alfred Barr Reading "Kiesler's Galaxy" used in Dorothy Miller Film, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels Duplicate (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Edited Version of Alfred Barr Recording used in Dorothy Miller Film, 1980; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels Includes notes about recording (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Outtakes of Alfred Barr Recording used in Dorothy Miller Film, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Oversized Clippings from Box 54, Folder 12, 1963-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
  - Loren MacIver, 1938-1998; 8.4; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains material related to Charlton's film on Loren MacIver, a painter of abstract landscapes. Included are notes, scripts, shooting cards, shot lists, printing plates, distribution information, research, and photographic material. There are also 2 film reels, trims, and canisters of 35 mm photographs, and folders about the subsequent screening of the film at various locations. A few photographs about the Loren MacIver film are in the photographic materials series.
    - Loren MacIver Letters to Maryette Charlton, 1962 August-1963 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 55, Folder 11-13)
    - Loren MacIver Letters to Maryette Charlton, 1963 March-November; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 56)
      - Loren MacIver Correspondence, 1956-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 5-8)
      - Art in America Correspondence, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Film Correspondence, 1956-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 10-11)
      - Loren MacIver Book Expenses Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - Maryette Charlton Lecture Correspondence, 1959-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Ingram Merrill Grant Application, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Film Bills and Expenses, 1957-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Film Brochure Layout, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Film Brochure Printing Plates, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 17)
      Oversized plates housed in Box 82.
    - Film Brochure Updated Material, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Film Contracts, 1964-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Film Distributor - Museum at Large, Ltd., 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Film Distributor - Radim Film Images, 1963-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Film Distribution and Screenings, 1972-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 4-5)
    - Film Editing and Scripts, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Film Editing Cards, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Film Editing Notes and Screening Feedback, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Film Preservation, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Film Print Purchases List, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Film Rentals, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Film Research at Columbia University, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 12-13)
    - Film Research Notes, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Film Screenings, Archival Resource Key (Box 57)
      - Brussels Film Festival, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - Corcoran Gallery, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 17)
      - New York Cultural Center, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - Paris, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Phillips Collection, circa 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Film Screenings, Archival Resource Key (Box 58)
      - Public Screenings, 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Mailing List, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Screening Notes, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Attendance and Feedback, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Retrospective Publicity, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Williams College, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Film Screenings List and Notes, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Film Screening Notes, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Film Scripts, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
    - Film Shooting Cards, circa 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Film Shot List, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Film Shot List Bound Volume, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Film Shot List, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Film "Title Shooting" Cards, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 82.
    - Festival of Women's Films, Archival Resource Key (Box 58)
      - Correspondence and Programs, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 16)
      - Audience Feedback Letters, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 17)
      - Publicity, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 18-19)
      - Poster, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 20)
      - Printed Material, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 21)